hello folks I'm Shashank and you're
watching ditto insurance today we have a
very interesting video where if you
stick around till the end you will know
how you can increase your base health
coverage from M 10 lakh or 20 lakh even
up to 1 CR rupees now to talk about this
special feature I have with me our
senior program manager here Ajay welcome
Ajay now a straight away to the
question is there a way that someone can
increase their base
coverage of their health policy yeah
Shashank so first of all glad to be here
um so I mean when it comes to your base
coverage I mean couple of people keep
asking me like is this enough is this
enough they go for a 20 lakh plan or 25
lakh plan and still they feel with
medical inflation so high so will that
be sufficient enough to take care of my
medical expens
so I mean usual workarounds are I mean
we usually recommend plans with good
bonuses right so that that kind of
increases the plan over the next couple
of years but even then if people want an
extra cover okay something they can look
for are super
topups yeah so initially there used to
be a concept called as topup okay and uh
you know nowadays they've become a
little redundant so basically that
worked in a way where say for example
I'm having a 25 lakh plan okay let's
forget the concept of bonus for now
let's just look at it that you know you
have a health insurance plan okay and it
is around say 20 lakhs right so now say
for example someone gets a
hospitalization okay and in this
hospitalization entire 20 lakhs is wiped
out okay so now there's nothing so
that's when the concept of top up comes
into picture right so so let's take an
example okay let's take an insurance
policy okay let's forget all the bonuses
and all that that I spoke about okay say
someone has a 10 lakh plan okay now say
this person got a particular claim say
they had some accident or whatever
unfortune situation and the bill came to
around 15 lakhs right so 10 lakh goes
from the base policy okay so now this
what this person has cleverly done
they've probably taken a top of
right so now the top up what it does so
on top of the 10 lakhs now around 5
lakhs is still remaining right so that 5
lakh will be paid by the topup policy it
is a separate policy alog together but
it can be you know utilized with your
base policy right so the catch here is
though the 5 lakh is being taken care of
by the topup okay the top up will have
something called as a deductible okay
the deductible can be 5 lakhs or 10
lakhs say in this case say the
deductible was 10 lakh say the top up
was a 20 lakh policy with a 10 lakh
deductible which essentially means the
first 10 lakh would have been taken care
of by the base policy which is here I've
paid the 10 lakh right so initial 10
lakh or if I don't have a policy at all
and I have only a top of policy then
I'll have to pay that from my
hand my own yes yes okay so that's how a
topup works right and what again
happened was say even if a person says
okay I'll probably use an insurance
policy to take care of the initial 10
lakhs so that my topup gets activated if
there's another hospitalization in the
same year then again the person has to
pay the 10 lakh for the topup to get
activated so you need to pay the
deductible again yes so the deductible
had to be paid again right so to tackle
this issue okay companies brought up
something called as a super topper okay
so here the deductable just has to be
paid once once in an year or once in the
like once in a year once in a year
during that you know the rual because
here there say that in the topups issue
say if there are three hospitalizations
three times the person gets into
hospital every time the person might
have to keep paying the deductible right
which is say 10 lakhs 10 laks 10 lakhs
only then the top up kicks in and the
amount you know gets deducted which
again is a huge problem right because
the insurance will probably just support
it once maybe during the first
deductible it's sufficient or know best
caseen sometimes it might touch the
second deductible right so why to have
this kind of a problem right so that's
why I think now topups are hardly there
okay you only have the super top-ups
luckily right so in the super top up you
just pay the deductible once in the year
and say if there are three
hospitalizations here for the second and
third hospitalization you don't have to
pay the deductible the super topup does
the job for you okay a now I have a
question who should get a super top up
do you think I would need a super topup
do you think uh my friend would need a
super topup who who who is super topup
for I mean see super topups just you
know give that additional kind of a
support okay so if you have a very good
Su insur with a good bonus I mean and if
your agent or adviser or whoever has
given you the optimum amount okay that
should be good enough but a super to is
just to give you that additional you
know feeling of security that uh you
know you have something extra on top of
that right to kind of take care and a
lot of people look at it from the
affordability perspective right so that
you know if I'm having another 25 lakhs
or another one CR on top of my base
policy right if my base policy is coming
at a lesser price that might help okay
but again it might have its drawbacks
right so the super toer policy is not
going to have the same you know exact
good features that your base policy is
having right so say for example the pre
and post Hospital ization expenses know
the duration might not be the same they
might have certain sublimit on room
rents so these kind of slight drawbacks
are there okay and again bonuses and all
might not be there right so that is
where the base policy shines so I would
never recommend having a super topup as
an alternate to a base policy right or a
base insurance policy is what I mean so
always have a very good base policies
def say definely there are instances
where super top s can help people is
that also what you're saying I mean yes
right so I mean say if someone decides
because it's on a case to case basis
someone decides that see I I have a very
strict budget no I don't want to go or
pay anything beyond this okay and uh you
know at the time of claims I'm okay to
go through some hassle because you know
when it comes to Super topup you got to
show some kind of a proof that you've
probably used the deductible right so
that again takes some time right so they
okay with all these things then Super
topup can also be a decent option to go
for understood so now that we know what
super top-ups are what benefits they
give and who is it for uh let's dive
into the top five Super topups that
people can consider in 2025 according to
ditto so what's uh first on your list
the best plan that I've seen is the Ala
super Health Plus right um so what I
really like about the plan is again
first let's look at the company metrics
uh so you have a 95% claim settlement
ratio over the last 3 years average and
uh even the network hospitals are good
so you have around 12,000 odd hospitals
so your chances of cashless is much more
higher okay coming to the features um
the plan offers a wide variety of
deductibles that is 1 to 15 lakhs okay
so depending on that the pricing will
change so higher the deductible lower
the price right for obvious reasons and
uh you have the SU insured up to 95
lakhs you can choose you know for
overall for the top of plan so that is a
very good feature coming to I mean
things like pre-post hospitalization
like I said it's not the best it's
around 30 to 60 days which again is
quite less like I mentioned before also
the other Basics are also covered like
you don't have any room rent restriction
which is really good for super topup cuz
some plans might have a you know capping
there yeah and one really good thing
about them is is that uh they if
somebody holds this particular super top
up for more than 5 years they offer a
waiver in the deductible itself right
which means that you know the deductible
is no more after 5 years okay um just
that they might not have a lot of
add-ons like other topup but it's a good
option to go for and uh very good thing
is there's no co- payment as well okay
even for senior citizens right so this
comes out to work really well if you're
looking for a very good you know
affordable and good super top up with
you know really good features so what
you're saying is adya ba has a pretty
good super to of plan yes covers all the
bases and definitely definitely when I
consider the other options you have a
solid plan with solid metrics from a
decent good brand all right so what's
next on your list the second one is care
enhance right um again why this is again
first and foremost coming to the metrics
uh so with care you've got a 90% claim
settlement ratio
uh I mean that is the average of 3 years
coming to I mean the network of
hospitals that's around 11,400 quite
close to Thea one which is that why it
is also a very good option okay when
you're going for cashless kind of a
feature right and uh coming to the major
features of the plan okay uh one very
good thing is the bonus right so in this
plan there's a 10% bonus okay compared
to other topups or super topups which
usually don't have these kind of bonus
features right so here the sum insur
will increase by 10% up to 100% right
and U there is a slight caveat that the
room rent restriction is only up to your
single private room right so that is
that uh prepost is decent which is
around 60 to 90 days and another very
good feature is the unlimited
restoration I mean topups I mean
providing a restoration itself is you
know something that's quite rare but
they are giving you an unlimited
restoration that's why you know this
kind of bumped up the list despite
having a single private room right which
is quite decent I mean considering an
hospitalization scenario all right so
this would be a solid option and also
they have a couple of add-ons as well
okay one is your um unlimited cover okay
which is during the lifetime of the
policy for one particular claim alone
you can claim unlimited sum insure right
and the second one is your air ambulance
okay which is I think like this kind of
an a ambulance it's kind of like a
helicopter for up to the sum insure that
you've opted for okay so in this plan if
you see since I spoke about sum inure up
to 95 lakhs you can take and the
deductible starts from 5 lakh onwards up
to 15 lakhs pretty decent plan in our
opinion correct now what's next on your
list so the next one would be the ICI
activate booster okay uh so here coming
to the policy uh the Claims Settlement
ratio is little on the lower end which
is around 85% which is theage
and then you have the network of
Hospital which is only around
7,500 so the metrics again are not the
best if you go for but uh you know when
it comes to the features okay they have
the highest pre and post hospitalization
expenses right so as in the duration the
interval is quite good which is around
90 to 180 days right compared to any
other policy this is really good which
is the highest in super topups I've seen
till now okay on top of that another
area they shine is they offer up to 3
crores for their sumon short which again
is quite High I mean till now we've just
spoken up to 95 lakhs whereas here it's
going up to 3 crores so that again is a
flagship feature that they're offering
okay uh coming to few other caveats
another is the single private room
restriction so that kind of a
restriction alone is there um but again
you know you have a couple of very good
add-ons okay like the jump start okay
okay which wherein they reduce the
pre-existing waiting period which will
you know benefit a lot of people if they
are having lifestyle conditions and a
list that they probably are know
offering the other one is the claim
protector which takes care of things
like your consumables which could be
like your mask PP kits those syringes
those kind of things which are
non-medical and the inflation protector
which you know makes sure that your Su
insured increases with inflation so you
don't have to worry that you know is my
Su insure good enough you know couple of
years down the line so these are some
very good features that they're offering
so it's jam-packed with a lot of good
features they also you know presumably
have a feature where uh you know you can
wave off the deductible as well okay a
now before we head to the last two
policies um I'd like to you know remind
our viewers that folks if you are
feeling lost or confused uh if the super
topup is really necessary for you then
you can book a free consultation with us
with the link in the description and let
me remind you that this is a special
link for our YouTube audience so that
you don't have to wait in the queue now
Ajay what's next in your list so that
would be the HDFC oro's medure policy um
so this doesn't have such a high Su
insured you've got up to 20 lakhs and
the deductible options are also limited
is usually 4 to 5 lakhs it does the
basics well like you don't have any
rumor and restrictions or anything as
such but that is um 10% co- payment if
someone reaches the age of 80 and above
so that is something and the pre and
post hospitalization expense is 30 to 60
days okay so it's a basic super topup it
does everything well the good thing is
the metrics right so if you see with
HDFC here go the claim settlement ratio
is 98% and you have around 12,500 or
network hospitals as well so that is
where you know this super top of shines
that it is very reliable perfect now
finally let's head to the last one uh
yeah final one would be the nea's health
recharge okay uh which again coming to
neaba it has a 91% claim settlement
ratio over the last 3 years the network
of hospitals is around 10,000 which is
decent okay but you do have better
options with ala or HDFC or go right and
again care as well coming to the
deductibles you have options from 3 lakh
up to 10 lakh and the sum insured you
have is up to 95 lakhs right com coming
to your pre and post hospitalizations it
is uh 60 to 90 days right which is quite
decent I mean I've told you how it works
in the other policies as well right and
um you know a good feature is that they
also have this wav of your deductible
after 5 years some of the drawbacks is
that you have only up to a single
private room so that restriction is
there and the major drawback being they
do have subl limits right so for certain
things like certain mental disorders and
modern treatments modern robotic
surgeries as well I guess right so they
have something like a sublimit right
which might know considerably affect the
plan uh that being said they also have a
bonus which is around 5% if there's not
been any claims during that year and
that increases up to 50% which will
substantially increase your sum insure
yeah so this would be the fifth option
all right a so you've taken us
[Music]
througha care DFC ICI and finally neaba
uh I think this pretty much sums up the
whole context of the video so thank you
so much for joining us and uh helping
our audience understand how super topups
work and uh if they even need a super
topup in the first place so folks I am
sure that by now you have realized if
you really need a super top up and if
you do which is the best one for you so
thank you so much a for joining us and
folks if you like this video drop a like
share this with someone who you think
might need a super topup and if you are
looking for a free consultation with
ditto then head to the link in the
description and book your free call I'll
see you guys in the next one until then
Happy Insurance hunting